<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Demo | Murashov I.V.</title>
    <link>https://neve7mind.github.io/en/category/demo/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neve7mind.github.io/en/category/demo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Demo</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neve7mind.github.io/media/icon_hu26bb6856b9ac2495d8c3fccce32364c5_204127_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Demo</title>
      <link>https://neve7mind.github.io/en/category/demo/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git version control</title>
      <link>https://neve7mind.github.io/en/post/post2_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neve7mind.github.io/en/post/post2_git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-version-control&#34;&gt;About Version Control&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is “version control”, and why should you care? Version control is a system that records changes to a file or set of files over time so that you can recall specific versions later. For the examples in this book, you will use software source code as the files being version controlled, though in reality you can do this with nearly any type of file on a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;local-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Local Version Control Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people’s version-control method of choice is to copy files into another directory (perhaps a time-stamped directory, if they’re clever). This approach is very common because it is so simple, but it is also incredibly error prone. It is easy to forget which directory you’re in and accidentally write to the wrong file or copy over files you don’t mean to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deal with this issue, programmers long ago developed local VCSs that had a simple database that kept all the changes to files under revision control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;1.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;centralized-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Centralized Version Control Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next major issue that people encounter is that they need to collaborate with developers on other systems. To deal with this problem, Centralized Version Control Systems (CVCSs) were developed. These systems (such as CVS, Subversion, and Perforce) have a single server that contains all the versioned files, and a number of clients that check out files from that central place. For many years, this has been the standard for version control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup offers many advantages, especially over local VCSs. For example, everyone knows to a certain degree what everyone else on the project is doing. Administrators have fine-grained control over who can do what, and it’s far easier to administer a CVCS than it is to deal with local databases on every client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this setup also has some serious downsides. The most obvious is the single point of failure that the centralized server represents. If that server goes down for an hour, then during that hour nobody can collaborate at all or save versioned changes to anything they’re working on. If the hard disk the central database is on becomes corrupted, and proper backups haven’t been kept, you lose absolutely everything — the entire history of the project except whatever single snapshots people happen to have on their local machines. Local VCSs suffer from this same problem — whenever you have the entire history of the project in a single place, you risk losing everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;2.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;distributed-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Distributed Version Control Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where Distributed Version Control Systems (DVCSs) step in. In a DVCS (such as Git, Mercurial or Darcs), clients don’t just check out the latest snapshot of the files; rather, they fully mirror the repository, including its full history. Thus, if any server dies, and these systems were collaborating via that server, any of the client repositories can be copied back up to the server to restore it. Every clone is really a full backup of all the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, many of these systems deal pretty well with having several remote repositories they can work with, so you can collaborate with different groups of people in different ways simultaneously within the same project. This allows you to set up several types of workflows that aren’t possible in centralized systems, such as hierarchical models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;3.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How was my week?</title>
      <link>https://neve7mind.github.io/en/post/post1_last-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neve7mind.github.io/en/post/post1_last-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday-is-a-hard-day&#34;&gt;Monday is a hard day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been visiting my parents since Saturday. Joined an online lecture, but instead of going to bed like every good student would, he took the initiative at the top and presented a report on operating system processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon I returned to Moscow. More suburban train I hate only 2 commuter trains. The smell of phantom feces, wherever they sit, the provincials arguing about what beers they will open after the next stop, the great relocation of hares to neighboring carriages when conductors, aggressive grannies, privatized 2 rows and praising the authoritarian regime, established in the country (during the time of Stalin, of course). In order to somehow endure such manifestations of the aforementioned mass, I put on headphones and it saves&amp;hellip; But not for long: every 2 stations at the beginning of the car begin to appear county commentators with loudspeakers, from which, the eardrums burst like balloons launched at the Kremlin, and ears twisted into a tube. They seem to have everything: a raincoat, a towel, swimming trunks, a welding machine, ice cream, headphones, a Makarov pistol and contraceptives (I think the most necessary for the carriage contingent) - as they say, everything - from a loaf to a condom, and all of a hundred rubles. I think the only thing they don’t have is another salesman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an hour on the train and half an hour on the bus, I find myself at home, where I translate my spirit and sit down to do my homework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday-and-wednesday-are-hard-days&#34;&gt;Tuesday and Wednesday are hard days&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night before, having decided to make a difference in my life, I got up at 6:00 in the morning, sleeping the most five hours in the last week. With closed eyes he made coffee and a lab. I went to volleyball and in the evening I met my brother in the craft - a friend-&lt;del&gt;masochist&lt;/del&gt; programmer. Overnight we wrote in Java. After a 1.5-hour sleep, he came to the university, where he died two couples in a row. Having failed, he went home to sleep, but since there is a lot of work, and in a day of only 24 hours (which genius came up with this!?), the day’s sleep made up a couple of hours, after which I did my hw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thursday-is-a-hard-day-either&#34;&gt;Thursday is a hard day either&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to couples, after which I taught mathematics to my sadistic student. Briefly about him: this creature is not deprived of a sense of humor, and therefore for two hours I was a boiling kettle with red eyes (from lack of sleep!). Yes, yes, I had to edit all the puzzles in which the answer resembled at least the number 300. You just can’t imagine how much excitement this beautiful creature has had every time it’s reminded me that killing is worth eight to 20 years, because that’s the only thing that’s kept me sitting in place since these stupid theses like &amp;lsquo;2 {0.5} = 1&amp;rsquo;, &amp;ldquo;You can’t hit kids&amp;rdquo; and all that crap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having heroically gone through these trials, I went to bed exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday---so-we-survived&#34;&gt;Friday - so we survived&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extremely happy, since I realize that the work week has ended and the working weekend has begun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I repent, I am sinful. I could have done much more if I had planned my time correctly and restored the regime. But in order to do that, we have to do all the labs, and in order to do all the labs, we have to find time for them, and in order to do them, we have to do all the labs, we have to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish everyone peace and goodness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
